Unzipped. Unwrapped. Unleashed!
Full Tilt Boogie is a documentary film directed by Sarah Kelly.
A documentary about the production of From Dusk Till
Dawn (1996) and the people who made it.
Self, played by Rick Stribling.
Self, played by Kevin Bondy.
Self, played by Amy Minda Cohen.
Self, played by Elizabeth Avellan.
Self, played by Dieter Busch.
Self, played by Cecilia Montiel.
Janis Lyn Joplin (January 19, 1943 – October 4, 1970)
was an American singer and songwriter.
One of the most iconic and successful rock performers of her era, she was noted for
her powerful mezzo-soprano vocals and her "electric" stage presence.
In 1967, Joplin rose to prominence following an appearance at the Monterey Pop Festival, where she was the lead
singer of the then little-known San Francisco psychedelic rock band Big Brother and the Holding Company.
After releasing two albums with the band, she left Big Brother to continue as a solo artist with her
own backing groups, first the Kozmic Blues Band and then the Full Tilt Boogie Band.
She performed at the 1969 Woodstock Festival and on
the Festival Express train tour.
Five singles by Joplin reached the US Billboard Hot 100, including a cover of the Kris
Kristofferson song "Me and Bobby McGee", which posthumously reached number one in March 1971.
Her most popular songs include her cover versions of "Piece of My Heart", "Cry Baby", "Down on Me", "Ball and
Chain", and "Summertime", as well as her original song "Mercedes Benz", which was her final recording.
Joplin died of a heroin overdose in 1970, at the age of 27, after releasing three
albums (two with Big Brother and the Holding Company and one solo album).
A second solo album, Pearl, was released in January
1971, three months after her death.
It reached number one on the Billboard 200.
She was posthumously inducted into the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame in 1995.
Rolling Stone ranked Joplin  number 28 on its 2008 list of the "200 Greatest
Singers of All Time", dropping to number 78 in the 2023 list.
As of 2013, she remains one of the top-selling vocalists in the United States, with Recording
Industry Association of America (RIAA) certifications of 18.5 million albums sold.
The film explores themes of movie business, stuntman,
swimming pool, hot tub, special effects.